Guide to the George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana Records, 1931-1981
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana records 1931-1981
University Archives, Duke University
George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana.
35 Linear Feet approx. 27,500 Items
The purpose of the George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana is to collect materials concerning the history and literature of the Southern United States.
Collection includes correspondence, annual reports, disbursements and other material.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer between 1973-2008.
Historical Note
The George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana (sometimes referred to as the George Washington Flowers Memorial Collection) honors George Washington Flowers, a trustee of Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) from 1897-1918. Some of his children graduated from Trinity College, including Robert Lee Flowers, President of Duke University from 1941-1948. The collection was established and endowed by his children for the purpose of collecting materials concerning the history and literature of the Southern United States. The Flowers Collection of Southern Americana is part of and managed by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Material includes correspondence, annual reports, disbursements, and other material such as acquisition cards related to the development of the George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Collection development (Libraries)
Duke University. Library
Southern States -- Library resources
Southern States -- Literary collections
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1933-1945: A -- Gittman's Bookshop (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1945: Glazebrook -- Roberds (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1945: Rosenbach -- Zeitter (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1947: A -- Z (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948: St. Chambers -- Morris
  - Correspondence: 1947-1948: Museum -- Wilson (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949: A -- Z
  - Correspondence, 1949-1950: Argosy -- Scotland Co.
  - Correspondence, 1949-1950: Seven Gables -- Young, Misc. (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1959: A -- Z
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952: A -- Z (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953: A -- Z; Personal
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954: A -- Graydon
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954: Hackett -- Taylor (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1955: A -- Z
  - Correspondence, 1959-1963: A -- R (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1963: S -- Z (Box 10)
  - Disbursements, 1961-1963
  - Correspondence, 1952-1962: Harkin -- Zucker (Box 11)
  - Annual Reports, 1937-1978
  - Disbursements, 1957-1959
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1968: A -- S (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1968: T -- Z (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1970: A -- Z
  - Annual Reports (Box 15)
  - Disbursements, 1966-1968
  - Lists, 1931-1938 (Box 16)
  - Office Files
  - Annual Reports, 1931-1936 (Box 17)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1941-1947
  - Acquisition Cards, 1946-1951 (Box 18)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1951-1954 (Box 19)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1954-1958 (Box 20)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1958-1961 (Box 21)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1961-1963 (Box 22)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1963-1965 (Box 23)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1965-1968 (Box 24)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1969-1972 (Box 25)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1972-1974 (Box 26)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1973-1975 (Box 27)
  - Acquisition Cards, 1979-1981